Harmeet Kaur

Coding Trainee



iharmeetk@gmail.com



07533206225



West Bromwich B71 2QG

Professional Summary

A bright and talented graduate with upper second-class Master of Computer application, about to complete full stack developer coding traineeship. I have over four- year experience of software development in Python and IDEs - PyCharm, school and python teaching/trainings experience. Technical experience in supporting applications which use an object-oriented programming language (JavaScript). Experience in using Pandas python libraries during development lifecycle. Excellent experience in PHP, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, writing SQL Queries, Stored procedures, functions, packages, tables, views, triggers.

Professional Qualification

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (Coding trainee) IT CAREER SWITCH, London September 2023 - Present

Master of Computer Applications Lovely Professional University, India (2018) Upper Second Class (2:1)

UK ENIC - RQF Level 7 / SCQF Level 11 / COFW Level 7

MSc in Information Technology Guru Nanak dev University, India (2017) Distinction

UK ENIC - RQF Level 7 / SCQF Level 11 / COFW Level 7

Bachelor of Computer Applications Guru Nanak dev University, India (2014) Distinction

UK ENIC - RQF Level 7 / SCQF Level 11 / COFW Level 7

Professional Experience

Aug 2020 - Present

IT CAREER SWITCH, London

Coding Trainee

- Developing programming skills using Python3, HTML 5, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP and Web Development.
- Undertake Python, PHP, React JS, MySQL, Rest API retrieval Training as a Full stack developer.
- Exploring multiple in-house projects for utilizing skills acquired on above technologies.
- Developing and Deploying Web Projects and deploying the same on GIT Hub Repository and website.
- Two major Projects Gazetteer, Company Directory available on my own GitHub and Website.
- Building new projects using REACT JS, Express JS using Web Tool Sets provided at IT Career switch.
- Developing projects for Authorization, Authentication, Encryption, Decryption.
- Gained proficiency in using the Command Line and Git for version control.
- Practiced Test-Driven Development (TDD) with JavaScript, ensuring code reliability and quality.
- Built a persistent API to facilitate data retrieval and manipulation.

- Performed testing and debugging applications end-to-end for any glitches and performance issues.
- Coordinating with front-end developers to support application, old databases to enhance their performance & functionality.
- Developed Student Enrolment application to support organizational objectives and strategic plans, improving enrolment and maintain student records using Django 4.2
- Transformed data using visual interface Tableau, Power BI through which I eventually helped to save time up to 70%.
- Wrote python scripts to parse xml, csv documents to load data.
- Used pandas to extract data and parse it, remove outliers, sort, append, merge.
- Used various libraries like matplotlib for line, bar, scatter, pie plotting.
- Worked with various libraries Keras, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow for various algebra operations in Machine learning project.
- Extensively used DJANGO technologies, which includes forms, templates for communication with database in different forms.

Nov 2018 – September 2020

QUASTECH, India

Python Trainer

- Designing, developing, and delivering online and classroom trainings.
- Preparing training materials and presentations required for training programs.
- Developing new assignments and activities to expand learning opportunities for students.
- Delivering effective and easy to grasp IT training.
- Training students for hands on practical sessions.
- Employ differentiated teaching methods and incorporating audio and visual activities.
- Provide individualized instructions to keep all students at the expected skill level.
- Identify and organize field trips to enhance the curriculum and learning Curve.
- Developing and implementing discipline plans and work closely with at-risk students
- Conducting and supervising institutional examinations and practical.
- Scheduling batches for all subjects and batches.

Oct 2017 – September 2018

Cheema Public School, Kishankot India

Teaching Assistant

- Designing, preparing teaching materials, and delivering classroom trainings.
- Developing new assignments and activities to expand learning opportunities for students.
- Teaching students for hands on practical sessions on computer.
- Provide individualized instructions to keep all students at the expected grades.
- Identify and organize trips to enhance the curriculum and learning Curve.
- Improved Computer grades by 20% since stepping into role.
- Developing and implementing discipline plans and work closely with lower-grades students. by supporting students' academic. emotional, and social development.
- Monitored and recorded the progress of students and created individual plans for improvement.

Other Education

Bachelor in Computer Application Guru Nanak dev University, India (2014) Upper Second Class (2:1)

UK ENIC - RQF Level 7 / SCQF Level 11 / COFW Level 7

Python, CSS, HTML coding online coaching YouTube, W3Schools

Full-stack engineer, jQuery, JS IT Career Switch UK Codecademy

Additional Information

Systems Experience: PyCharm, Visual Studio Code (VS Code), Jupyter Notebook, Pydev (Eclipse), IDLE etc.

Framework Experience & Libraires: PyCharm, Django, NumPy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn etc.

Languages: Fluent in Punjabi & Hindi, understand intermediate level Urdu.

Hobbies: House renovations, playing snooker, bowling, basketball and planning days out.

PREVIOUS PROJECT WORK SUMMARY

BCA: Project on Travel Agency in ASP

MSc (IT)/MCA: Project on *Automobile Management System* in ASP.NET in C-SHARP **Python trainee**: Project on *My Cake Shop* on PyCharm in Django with PYMYSQL, HTML,

CSS

Project AS Python Trainer: Student Enrolment System.

Short Description: Student Enrolment System (SES) is designed to manage all the activities involved during the student enrolment process and their course data. The main objective of the enrolment system is to help staff members to enroll students and maintain their records.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Good Communication and Oratory Skills
- Supervisory and Teaching Skills
- Practical and Result Oriented Approach.
- Proactive Learning Acumen
- Team player

References – available on request